hello there it's been a little while I
wanted to do a video about this
coronavirus thing that you may have
heard of I'm gonna do this in one take
and so forgive me if it's not perfectly
articulated but I wanted to do it
reasonably spontaneously I'll put a
couple of notes here but I just wanted
to do it all in one here and so because
the circumstances of my life somewhat
insulate me from the fallout of all of
this I'm nowhere near as effective as
many many people are I've had a chance
to spend a lot of time talking to people
listening to people and getting a pretty
broad perspective on all of this and for
me the most important question to emerge
is the idea of how we have been for
decades whether consciously or not
whether we actually agree to it or not
we have been sacrificing resiliency for
efficiency and I say I hear no talk of
this whatsoever in the sort of legacy
mainstream media but there is importance
of the internet conversations about this
and I wanted to do my little tiny bit on
my youtube channel just to turn the
volume up on those questions and those
conversations because I think that for
me anyway it's the most important idea
to emerge from all of this and so what
I'm talking about is the trade-off that
inevitably exists between efficiency and
resiliency so as you increase efficiency
you also increase for Gillette fragility
it's an inevitability so for example the
just-in-time supply chains that so many
organizations work on meaning that
they're not having to hold stock they
don't have to have as much warehouse
space they don't have to you know
they're there less wastage all of that
kind of thing but because everything's
arriving just in time to be deliverable
on to the next step in the chain if that
chain gets interrupted at any point
there's no slack there to to be taken up
and so that the chain potentially
immediately collapses so this is
extremely fragile another idea is that
things run at primarily full capacity
right it's inefficient to have room
standing empty you know staff not
engaged in actually doing things all the
time and so you know cutbacks in wages
cost cutting exercises in
reducing premises costs etc etc means
that there is again no slack to be taken
up when when there is a surge in
tomorrow there's no slack taken up to be
shaken up I mean in the UK certainly
already the emergency rooms were
overwhelmed right that was already
excessive waiting times and emergency
rooms and so add a tiny little bit of
extra pressure to that and the whole
thing potentially falls apart so that's
another one and then the third example
I've got here is the notion of always
being optimized for one thing and this
is both people and equipment right so
when you're building a factory to make a
car for example the only thing that
factory knows how to make is cars to
repurpose that Factory is a major major
undertaking takes time it takes huge
capital staff are trained generally in
most organizations not all some already
do you know sort of more diverse
exposure to skills but in many
organisations each person in their
organization in in that organization is
trained to do one thing and one thing
only and they may do it very well but
that's all they know how to do and so
someone made a point in a conversation I
had that as global calamities go this is
a really gentle one you know it's like
you've got some important lessons to
learn here's a little kick up the
backside wake up learn these lessons
otherwise next time it's only going to
be much much worse you know it's
important to understand that although
nobody could have predicted six months
ago that we were going to you know have
a novel virus spreading around the globe
it was easy to predict it's a certainty
that at some point along the road there
is going to be an unexpected calamity
and the greater our ability to in a
general sense absorb the impact of the
unexpected the less of this kind of
nonsense you know the weather the
complete shutdown of absolutely bloody
everything and that we that we need to
see in the future and so I would like to
offer a few things just basically off
the top of my head types of suggestions
that will build resilience but we you
know it's going to be at the expense of
efficiency which in turn is at the
expense of profits and shareholder
returns and all of that kind of thing
and this has just got to be accepted or
or if shareholder returns and profits
are the most important thing then let's
be explicit about their let's say okay
we accept we were going to have a high
level of fragility because we want to
have high levels of profits but you know
you can't have both you can't have
resilience and efficiency at the same
time there's a trade-off to be made
right and a conversation needs to be had
to what extent are we willing to
sacrifice resilience in the pursuit of
profit you know at what point do we stop
in the pursuit of profit because we
recognize that it's in all of our
interests to have a certain amount of
resilience built into the economy right
and so we need to understand that there
is that trade-off being made all the
time during that front-and-center and
understand what we are doing so anyway
like I said a few examples of the types
of things we can be doing firstly at the
individual level I mean pretty obviously
if everybody had a couple of months of
stocks in the freezer and in the form of
dry goods and bottled water and so on it
means that nobody has to panic right
when when when something comes along
everyone's got a couple of months where
they don't have to panic if a
significant number of people had solar
systems generators whatever that kind of
thing you know this this can absorb
impact so you know building this in at
an at an individual level is step number
one step number two is to think about
businesses and companies happens they
make themselves more resilient and in
doing so contribute to the overall
resilience of the society and so things
like as I've already mentioned training
staff to be a bit more diverse in their
skill sets you know what I mean
encourage additional training and things
that are outside of their immediate
purview just to have that capacity that
spare capacity built-in when you're
building a factory instead of building
it and optimizing it to make that one
thing and that one thing only build it
in a modular way right it costs a little
bit more but by building in a modular
way you can take bits out put other bits
back in and very quickly and easily
repurpose that Factory to make new
things I mean imagine if you know a
vacuum cleaner Factory could be
repurposed overnight to start
manufacturing ventilators thousands of
them a day you know this kind of thing
is it's not technically speaking this
not a particularly difficult challenge
but as I've already said there is a
sacrifice of profit and a sacrifice of
efficiency involved at a at the next
level up of us at the government
societal level you could Institute a you
know like there's like there's army
reserves you know people they do two or
three weeks a year whatever it is of
training and they maintain a sort of
basic level of skills they're not full
army but they reserves and they can
support the army when when when when
there's when there's demand for them why
could we not do something similar with
medical reserves with construction
reserves with logistics reserves you
know and where everybody in the
population hair doesn't spend a couple
of weeks a year doing something that
isn't their normal job just to just to
keep their hand in so that if that thing
becomes needed you've got a whole bunch
of reserves and volunteers to do that
sound seems to me to be a relatively
simple way to build a massive amount of
spare capacity and thus resilience into
the economy so that's that's about it
I'm just a just a short video I'm gonna
make one more I want to talk also about
the lockdown and staying at home and
some of the opportunities that this
actually could present so I'll do
another one on that very shortly but for
now thank you very much for watching